Guide to the Andrei Voznesenskii Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 6: Photographs
  - Subseries 6.6: A.Voznesenskii with Colleagues, Friends, and Acquaintance
    - A.Voznesenskii with Dora Levcheva and Liubomir [Lyubomir?] Levchev in Australian.d., Six colour prints, some with short handwritten notes on the other side, some are slightly damaged. (Oversize 48, Folder 23)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with Dora Levcheva [Boneva?] and Liubomir [Lyubomir?] Levchev in Australia.
      Dora Levcheva [Boneva?]; Liubomir [Lyubomir?] Levchev.
    - A.Voznesenskii with Evgenii Pasternak and othersn.d., A photocopy of a print, slightly damaged. (Oversize 49, Folder 1)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with Evgenii Pasternak and others.
      Evgenii Pasternak.
    - A.Voznesenskii with Frederic Starr [?]n.d., A print attached to a piece of paper, with short handwritten notes / marks on both sides, slightly damaged. (Oversize 49, Folder 2)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with Frederic Starr [?].
      Frederic Starr [?].
    - A.Voznesenskii with Harold [?] Taylorn.d., A print with a long handwritten note on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 3)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with Harold [?] Taylor.
      Harold [?] Taylor.
    - A.Voznesenskii with Il'ia Kutik, Liuba D'Herluguian, and Andrew Wachtel2000; n.d., Five colour prints, some with handwritten notes on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 4)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with Il'ia Kutik, Liuba D'Herluguian, and Andrew Wachtel.
      Il'ia Kutik; Liuba D'Herluguian; Andrew Wachtel.
    - A.Voznesenskii with Lilia Brik and othersn.d., A damaged black-and-white print with a handwritten note on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 5)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with Lilia Brik and others.
      Lilia Brik.
    - A.Voznesenskii with Lord Battel [Battle?]February 1992, A damaged black-and-white print with short handwritten notes on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 6)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with Lord Battel [Battle?].
      Lord Battel [Battle?].
    - A.Voznesenskii with Mariia Zhdanovich [?] in Berlinn.d., A colour print with several handwritten notes on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 7)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with Mariia Zhdanovich [?] in Berlin.
      Mariia Zhdanovich [?].
    - A.Voznesenskii with L. [Liuben?] Georgiev and others in Sofia, Bulgaria05.12.1983, A black-and-white print with several short handwritten notes and a printed photographer's copyright on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 8)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with L. [Liuben?] Georgiev and others in Sofia, Bulgaria. There is a handwritten note from L. [Liuben?] Georgiev to A.Voznesenskii (among other handwritten notes) on the other side of the print.
      L. [Liuben?] Georgiev.
    - A.Voznesenskii with [Martin?] Trautwein, the writer Andrei Bitov, and others at European Artists Forum in Amsterdam12.10-14.1987, Two black-and-white prints of different size, both with pieces of paper attached, with handwritten notes and printed information on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 9)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with [Martin?] Trautwein, the writer Andrei Bitov, and others at European Artists Forum in Amsterdam.
      [Martin?] Trautwein; Andrei Bitov.
    - A.Voznesenskii with Mila Los' and others1978, A black-and-white print with handwritten notes and a printed photographer's copyright on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 10)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with Mila Los' and others.
      Mila Los' .
    - A.Voznesenskii with Nikolai Aleksandrovich Kozyrev at Crimean observatoryn.d., A black-and-white print with a handwritten note on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 11)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with Nikolai A. Kozyrev at Crimean observatory.
      Nikolai A. Kozyrev.
    - A.Voznesenskii with Russian rock musician Andrei Makarevichn.d., A black-and-white print with a short handwritten note on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 12)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with Russian rock musician Andrei Makarevich.
      Andrei Makarevich.
    - A.Voznesenskii with Russian rock musician Boris Grebenshchikovn.d., A colour print with a short handwritten note and printed technical notes on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 13)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with Russian rock musician Boris Grebenshchikov.
    - A.Voznesenskii with Russian TV presenter and critic Sviatoslav Belza, the composer Nikolai Petrov and othersn.d., Five colour prints of different size with handwritten notes and / or handwritten / printed photographers' copyrights on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 14)
      Sviatoslav Belza; Nikolai Petrov.
    - A.Voznesenskii with Soviet writer Sergei [?] Mikhalkov, Bulgarian communist leader Todor Zhivkov, and others in Sofia, Bulgarian.d., A black-and-white print with a handwritten note and a printed photographer' s copyright on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 15)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with Soviet writer Sergei [?] Mikhalkov, Bulgarian communist leader Todor Zhivkov, and others in Sofia, Bulgaria.
      Sergei [?] Mikhalkov; Todor Zhivkov.
    - A.Voznesenskii with Tatiana Iakovleva and othersn.d., A black-and-white print with a short handwritten note on the other side, slightly damaged. (Oversize 49, Folder 16)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with Tatiana Iakovleva and others.
      Tatiana Iakovleva.
    - A.Voznesenskii with Tera and Mara Ragann.d. [November 1990?], A black-and-white print with a short handwritten note and a printed technical note on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 17)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with Tera and Mara Ragan.
      Tera Ragan; Mara Ragan.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the actor Mikhail Kazakov, the philologist Efim Berenshtein [?], and others in Peredelkino near Boris Pasternak House-Museumn.d., A black-and-white print, slightly damaged. (Oversize 49, Folder 18)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with the actor Mikhail Kazakov, the philologist Efim Berenshtein [?], and others in Peredelkino near Boris Pasternak House-Museum.
      Mikhail Kazakov; Efim Berenshtein [?]; Boris Pasternak.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the actor Oleg Tabakov and othersn.d., Two colour prints of different size, one print with printed technical information on the other side, the second print with a photographer's copyright on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 19)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the actor Oleg Tabakov and others.
      Oleg Tabakov.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the artist Francesco Clemente [?] and others at the inauguration of an exhibition 1992, A damaged black-and-white print with a photographer's copyright and her address (both printed and handwritten) and a handwritten note on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 20)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with the artist Francesco Clemente [?] and others at the inauguration of an exhibition. There is a handwritten note on the other side mentioning the name of the gallery (illegible).
      Francesco Clemente [?]; Marianna Volkov.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the artists Tatiana Lavrova and Arkadii Raikinn.d. [1976?], A black-and-white print with handwritten notes on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 21)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with the artists Tatiana Lavrova and Arkadii Raikin.
      Tatiana Lavrova; Arkadii Raikin.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the ballerina Maiia Plisetskaia and othersApril 1977; n.d., Five black-and-white and colour prints of different size, some with handwritten notes / printed technical notes / photographers' information on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 22)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the ballerina Maiia Plisetskaia and others.
      Maiia Plisetskaia.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the ballerina Ul'iana Lopatkina, Bella Akhmadulina, Boris Messerer, and othersn.d., Eight black-and-white prints of different size, one photo with a handwritten note on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 23)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the ballerina Ul'iana Lopatkina, Bella Akhmadulina, Boris Messerer, and others.
      Ul'iana Lopatkina; Bella Akhmadulina; Boris Messerer.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the clergy at Boris Pasternak's graven.d., Three black-and-white prints of different size, slightly damaged, with the printed photographer's information on the other side, one print with a small yellow piece of paper attached, with a short handwritten note on it. (Oversize 49, Folder 24)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the clergy at Boris Pasternak's grave.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the composer Dmitrii Shostakovich and others1963, Two prints of different size, one with a short handwritten note on the other side. The second print is damaged. (Oversize 49, Folder 25)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the composer Dmitrii Shostakovich and others.
      Dmitrii Shostakovich.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the composer Mikael Tariverdiev and the actor Igor' Staryginn.d., Four black-and-white prints of different size, damaged, one print with a short handwritten note. (Oversize 49, Folder 26)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the composer Mikael Tariverdiev and the actor Igor' Starygin.
      Mikael Tariverdiev; Igor' Starygin.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the composer Rodion Shchedrin and othersJanuary 1974; n.d., Two black-and-white prints of different size, slightly damaged, with handwritten notes on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 27)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the composer Rodion Shchedrin and others.
      Rodion Shchedrin.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the curator of the "TV-Gallery" Nina Zaretskaian.d., A black-and-white print with a long handwritten note on the other side. (Oversize 49, Folder 28)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with the curator of the "TV-Gallery" Nina Zaretskaia.
      Nina Zaretskaia; Marat [?] Gel'man; Andy Warhol.; "TV-Gallery".
    - A.Voznesenskii with the Gantsevichis and Lavrova [?]October 197[?], A black-and-white print with short handwritten notes on both sides, slightly damaged. (Oversize 50, Folder 1)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with the Gantsevichis and Lavrova [?].
    - A.Voznesenskii with the Georgian politician E.A.Shevardnadze, the sculptor Zurab Tsereteli, the singer Zurab Sotkilava, and othersn.d., Five colour prints of different size, one print with handwritten notes on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 2)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the Georgian politician Eduard A. Shevardnadze, the sculptor Zurab Tsereteli, the singer Zurab Sotkilava, and others.
      Eduard A. Shevardnadze; Zurab Tsereteli; Zurab Sotkilava.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the Lenkom Theater director Mark Zakharov, the composer Aleksei Rybnikov, the actor Nikolai Karachentsov, and othersn.d., Five colour and black-and-white prints of different size, some with handwritten notes / a photographer's information on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 3)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the Lenkom Theater director Mark Zakharov, the composer Aleksei Rybnikov, the actor Nikolai Karachentsov, and others.
      Mark Zakharov; Aleksei Rybnikov; Nikolai Karachentsov.; Lenkom Theater.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the musician Mstislav Rostropovich, the journalist Egor Iakovlev, and others at "Moskovskie novosti"n.d., Two colour prints with handwritten notes and printed technical notes on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 4)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the musician Mstislav Rostropovich, the journalist Egor Iakovlev, and others at "Moskovskie novosti".
      Mstislav Rostropovich; Egor Iakovlev.; "Moskovskie novosti".
    - A.Voznesenskii with the painter [Lado?] Gudiashvili and others in Tbilisi, Georgia1981; n.d., Six black-and-white prints of different size, some with short handwritten notes on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 5)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the painter [Lado?] Gudiashvili and others in Tbilisi, Georgia.
      [Lado?] Gudiashvili.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the parodist Aleksandr Ivanov, Zoia Boguslavskaia, and othersn.d., A black-and-white print, damaged. (Oversize 50, Folder 6)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with the parodist Aleksandr Ivanov, Zoia Boguslavskaia, and others.
      Aleksandr Ivanov; Zoia Boguslavskaia.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the poet Konstantin Kedrov and othersn.d., A black-and-white print with a short handwritten note on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 7)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with the poet Konstantin Kedrov and others.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the poet Robert Rozhdestvenskii, Aliia Rozhdestvenskaia, and othersn.d., Three black-and-white prints of different size, slightly damaged, two of them with short handwritten notes / a photographer's information on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 8)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the poet Robert Rozhdestvenskii, Aliia Rozhdestvenskaia, and others.
      Robert Rozhdestvenskii; Aliia Rozhdestvenskaia.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the poets Andrei Dement'iev, Rasul Gamzatov, and others at VII Siezd Pisatelei SSSR [The VII Congress of Writers of Soviet Union]July 1981, Seven black-and-white prints with handwritten notes and a photographer's information on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 9)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the poets Andrei Dement'iev, Rasul Gamzatov, and others at VII Siezd Pisatelei SSSR [The VII Congress of Writers of Soviet Union].
      Andrei Dement'iev; Rasul Gamzatov.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the poets Bella Akhmadulina, Evgenii Evtushenko, Bulat Okudzhava, Mikhail Svetlov, Oleg Khlebnikov, the writer Vasilii Aksenov, and others1962; 10.14.1974; 1988; 1997; n.d., Seven black-and-white and colour prints of different size, some with short handwritten notes on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 10)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the poets Bella Akhmadulina, Evgenii Evtushenko, Bulat Okudzhava, Mikhail Svetlov, Oleg Khlebnikov, the writer Vasilii Aksenov, and others. Two photos were taken at Bulat Okudzhava's funeral.
      Bella Akhmadulina; Evgenii Evtushenko [Yevtushenko]; Bulat Okudzhava; Mikhail Svetlov; Oleg Khlebnikov; Vasilii Aksenov.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the politician Irina Khakamada and othersn.d., A damaged colour print with a short handwritten note on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 11)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with the politician Irina Khakamada and others.
      Irina Khakamada.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the scientist and writer Iurii Kariakin and the theater critic Aleksandr Borshchagovskiin.d., A black-and-white print with a handwritten note and a printed photographer's copyright on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 12)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with the scientist and writer Iurii Kariakin and the theater critic Aleksandr Borshchagovskii.
      Iurii Kariakin; Aleksandr Borshchagovskii.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the sculptor Ernst Neizvestnyin.d., A black-and-white print with a handwritten note and a printed photographer's copyright on the other side. Slightly damaged. (Oversize 50, Folder 13)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with the sculptor Ernst Neizvestnyi.
      Ernst Neizvestnyi.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the sculptor Zurab Tsereteli and others1978; n.d., Sixteen black-and-white and colour prints of different size, some with handwritten notes and / or a photographer's copyright on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 14)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the sculptor Zurab Tsereteli and others. Some pictures show A.Voznesenskii with Z.Tsereteli or alone, with their mutual project on the background, or the monument itself.
      Zurab Tsereteli.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the Taganka Theater director Iurii Liubimov, the film director Elem Klimov, Russian rock musician Aleksandr Gradskii, Zoia Boguslavskaia, and others1980s; n.d., Four black-and-white prints of different size, some damaged / with short handwritten notes / printed photographers' information on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 15)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the Taganka Theater director Iurii Liubimov, the film director Elem Klimov, Russian rock musician Aleksandr Gradskii, Zoia Boguslavskaia, and others. The first print pictures Iurii Liubimov and A.Voznesenskii at Vladimir Vysotskii's grave.
      Iurii Liubimov; Elem Klimov; Aleksandr Gradskii; Zoia Boguslavskaia; Vladimir Vysotskii.; Moskovskii teatr dramy i komedii na Taganke.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the U.S.Ambassador in Russia [?] Stessel and othersn.d., A black-and-white print, damaged, with handwritten notes on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 16)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with the U.S.Ambassador in Russia [?] Stessel and others.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the violinist and conductor Vladimir Spivakov, the ballerina Maiia Plisetskaia, and othersn.d., Four black-and-white prints of different size, one print with an attached piece of paper, with handwritten notes on both sides. (Oversize 50, Folder 17)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the violinist and conductor Vladimir Spivakov, the ballerina Maiia Plisetskaia, and others.
      Vladimir Spivakov; Maiia Plisetskaia.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the writer Andrei Bitov, the scientist Volf Schmidt [?], and othersn.d., Two black-and-white and colour prints, one print with short handwritten marks and a printed photographer's copyright on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 18)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the writer Andrei Bitov, the scientist Volf Schmidt [?], and others.
      Andrei Bitov; Volf Schmidt [?].
    - A.Voznesenskii with the writer Andrei Siniavskii, [?] Ozerov, and others1990 - February 1997; n.d., Three black-and-white and colour prints of different size, some with short handwritten notes and / or printed technical notes on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 19)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the writer Andrei Siniavskii, [?] Ozerov, and others. The last ptrint pictures A.Voznesenskii at A.Siniavskii's funeral in Paris.
      Andrei Siniavskii [Abram Terts].
    - A.Voznesenskii with the writer Daniil Granin, Riazanov [?], and others at St.-Petersburg State University of Trade Unionsn.d., A colour print with a short handwritten note and a printed technical note on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 20)
      A photo of A.Voznesenskii with the writer Daniil Granin, Riazanov [?], and others at St.-Petersburg State University of Trade Unions.
      Daniil Granin.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the writer [?] I.V.Abashidze and others at the celebration of Abashidze's 70th anniversary in Tbilisi, Georgia11.23-24.1979, Two black-and-white prints of different size, slightly damaged, with handwritten notes on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 21)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the writer [?] I.V.Abashidze and others at the celebration of Abashidze's 70th anniversary in Tbilisi, Georgia.
      I.V.Abashidze.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the writers Evgenii Popov, Vasilii Aksenov, and others n.d., Four colour prints with short handwritten and printed technical notes on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 22)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the writers Evgenii Popov, Vasilii Aksenov, and others. Two prints picture A.Voznesenskii with a handmade GULAG book from "beresta".
      Evgenii Popov; Vasilii Aksenov.
    - A.Voznesenskii with Zoia Boguslavskaia and others n.d., Twenty colour and black-and-white prints of different size, some with handwritten notes / printed technical notes / photographers' copyrights on the other side. (Oversize 50, Folder 23)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with Zoia Boguslavskaia and others Some pictures were taken in Tbilisi (Georgia) and Kislovodsk.
    - A.Voznesenskii with the singer Galina Vishnevskaia, the musician Mstislav Rostropovich, and others n.d., Six black-and-white prints of different size, some are co-attached, some are damaged, one print with a short handwritten note on the other side. (Othertype 51, Folder 1)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with the singer Galina Vishnevskaia, the musician Mstislav Rostropovich, and others. Some photos may have been taken in Italy.
      Galina Vishnevskaia; Mstislav Rostropovich.
    - A.Voznesenskii with unidentified people [1 of 5]1965 [March-April 1966?] - May 1991; n.d., Ten black-and-white and colour prints of different size, two of them attached to pieces of cartoon, and two photocopies of prints. Some items are damaged, some with short handwritten notes on the other side or both sides, some with handwritten / printed photographers' copyrights / other information on the other side. (Othertype 51, Folder 2)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with unidentified people. Some photos were taken in the USA. Notes are in Russian and English.
    - A.Voznesenskii with unidentified people [2 of 5]1971-04[?].09[?].2002; n.d., Sixty two black-and-white and colour prints of different size, some are incomplete / damaged, some with short handwritten notes / printed technical information / printed or handwritten photographers' copyrights / information on the other side. (Othertype 51, Folder 3)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with unidentified people. Notes are in Russian and English.
    - A.Voznesenskii with unidentified people [3 of 5]1967-2000[?]; n.d., Eighty four black-and-white and colour prints of different size, some are damaged, some with handwritten notes / handwritten or printed photographers' copyrights / other information on the other side or both sides. (Othertype 51, Folder 4)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with unidentified people. Notes are in Russian, Hebrew, and English.
    - A.Voznesenskii with unidentified people [4 of 5]1961-1999 / 2000[?]; n.d., Thirty nine black-and-white and colour prints of different size, some are damaged, some with handwritten notes / handwritten or printed photographers' copyrights / other information on the other side or both sides. (Othertype 51, Folder 5)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with unidentified people. Notes are in Russian, English, and Georgian [Armenian?].
    - A.Voznesenskii with unidentified people [5 of 5]n.d., Thirty eight black-and-white prints of different size, some are damaged, some with short handwritten notes / handwritten or printed photographers' information on the other side. (Othertype 51, Folder 6)
      Photos of A.Voznesenskii with unidentified people.
  - Subseries 6.7: A.Voznesenskii's Photos and Photo Portraits
    - A.Voznesenskii's photos and photo portraits [1 of 9]1993; n.d., Thirteen black-and-white and colour prints, mostly damaged, some with short handwritten notes on the other side. (Othertype 51, Folder 7)
      A.Voznesenskii's photos and photo portraits.
    - A.Voznesenskii's photos and photo portraits [2 of 9]n.d., Eleven black-and-white prints of different size, some with short handwritten notes / handwritten or printed photographers' copyrights / information on the other side / both sides. (Othertype 51, Folder 8)
      A.Voznesenskii's photos and photo portraits. Notes are in Russian and English.
    - A.Voznesenskii's photos and photo portraits [3 of 9]1978-1979; n.d., Thirteen black-and-white and colour prints of different size, mostly damaged, some with short handwritten notes / handwritten or printed photographers' information on the other side, and one photocopy of a print (14 items total). (Othertype 51, Folder 9)
      A.Voznesenskii's photos and photo portraits. Includes 6 prints of A.Voznesenskii at his parents' grave / the grave itself and 2 prints of A.Voznesenskii in Sverdlovsk (now Ekaterinburg) near Ipat'ievskii House.
      Nikolai II.
    - A.Voznesenskii's photos and photo portraits [4 of 9]01.25.1965-10.14.1977; 1980s; n.d., Two contact sheets, two photocopies of prints, one print in a mini photoalbum, and ten black-and-white prints (15 items total), some are damaged, all with handwritten notes / handwritten or printed photographers' information and / or other technical information on the other side. (Othertype 51, Folder 10)
      Contact sheets and A.Voznesenskii's photos and photo portraits.